NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
〜
Our team got them.
（南原(なんばら)）うちの班が確保したわ
Right. Aiko Tachibana and the boy.
そう 橘(たちばな)アイコとその少年も
I keep telling you.
Bring the girl over here now.
だから 何度も言ったでしょう
早く彼女をこっちに移しなさいって
There aren't proper facilities in Tokyo.
（伊佐津(いさづ)）
東京には 十分な施設が
整っていないからね
Are you still on this?
（南原）まだ言ってるの？
-And what about you?
-What?
（伊佐津）君のほうこそ
（南原）え？
When are you going to
burn down that red river?
（伊佐津）
いつになったら
あの赤い川を焼き払うんだい？
I don't know how you can say that.
よくそんな
ひと事みたいに言えるわね
You know full well how many
assets are stranded
マリグナント･マターに侵された
あの一帯に
in that area
the Malignant Matter has overtaken.
どれだけ有益な資産が
残されたままになっているかは
あなたも分かってるでしょ？
In fact, the very Matter
is arguably a national asset
それどころか
マター自体が研究対象として
すさまじい価値を持った
我が国の資産ともいえるわ
with incredible value
as a subject for research.
An asset?
Enough to risk all of humanity for?
（伊佐津）
資産？
人類の危機を天秤(てんびん)にかけるほどの？
Yes, in order to save us from this crisis.
その危機から脱するためのよ
Such a roundabout method.
（伊佐津）
回りくどいことを…
Anyway, what are you doing
about Yuya Kanzaki?
それより 神崎雄哉(かんざきゆうや)のほうは
どうなっている？
We'll question him soon.
聴取はこれから
At any rate,
I would appreciate it if you didn't
とにかく これ以上
うちの特務班の出番―
keep making me use my team.
増やさないでくれると
ありがたいわね
If we're inspected,
this will all be over.
監査が入ったら
そこで終わりなんだから
Feeling better?
（小佐波(おざなみ)）落ち着いた？
Yes. Thank you.
（アイコ）
はい ありがとうございます
警察の方ですか？
Are you with the police?
みたいなもの
バーストに関係する専門のね
Sort of. I work with
an agency involved with the Burst.
NANAMI OZANAMI
Did you come to my home?
私の家に来たのも？
You slipped right through our fingers.
見事に逃げられてしまったけど
すみません
I'm sorry.
Dr. Isazu from Kiryu Hospital
requested that we protect you.
（小佐波）
桐生(きりゅう)病院の伊佐津先生から―
身辺保護の依頼をもらったの
Can I see Dr. Isazu?
I have some questions I...
先生に会えますか？
聞きたいことが…
あっ…
Never mind.
（アイコ）いえ…
It's late. I'll take you
to see him when things quiet down.
もう遅いから
落ち着いたら 病院に送ってあげる
Thank you.
（アイコ）ありがとうございます
誰なんですか？
私をさらった あの転校生…
Who is that transfer student
who took me away?
（部下）
君が転校時に学園に提出した
プロフィールが
We discovered the transfer papers
you submitted
to the school were fraudulent.
偽造されたものであることは
判明している
Who are you working for?
What's your objective?
背後に誰かいるのか？
目的は？
なぜ 橘アイコを拉致した？
Why did you kidnap Aiko Tachibana?
やっぱり 分からないんですね
You don't know, do you?
How about some more juice?
ジュースおかわり どう？
（アイコ）あの…
So...
ん？
everything he told me is a lie, isn't it?
あの人が言ってたことって
やっぱり ウソなんですか？
（小佐波）あっ 何て？
What did he say?
That my...
私の… あっ…
お母さんと弟が生きてるって
That my mom and brother are alive.
爆心地で
まだ２人が生きてるって！
He said they're still alive
at Ground Zero!
（アイコ）あっ
（ピッ）
はっ！
（小佐波）
残念だけれど
お父さんが事故で亡くなったあと
Unfortunately, after your father died
in the accident,
お母さんも弟さんも
your mother and brother
were confirmed killed in the Burst.
バーストの際に
確かに亡くなってる
It's in the official records of the
Control Agency of Artificial Creatures.
人工生体汚染災害対策庁の
公式記録に残されてたわ
はっ…！
なぜ わざわざ手の込んだ手段で
彼女と接触した？
Why did you go to such lengths
to get near her?
あっ
That's a special plane.
Could you please not touch it?
（雄哉）
特製なんです
触らないでもらえませんか？
あっ
大事な部活の備品なんで
It's important to my school club.
If you really must have it,
I guess I could give it to you.
どうしても欲しければ
差し上げないことはありませんが…
うむ
くっ！
If you've got questions,
（雄哉）取り調べるなら
then hurry and take me to the station.
さっさと
署に連れてってくださいよ
You have to register me, right?
調書も
取らなきゃいけないでしょ？
（部下）くっ！
Or is this the only place
you can do your questioning?
それとも こんなとこでしか
調べられないんですか？
んっ
Fine. We'll take you
to a more appropriate location.
いいだろう
しかるべき場所に移動しよう
（ピーッ）
（黒瀬(くろせ)）よし きた！
Yes! There it is!
I knew that paper plane
would come in handy!
役に立つじゃないか 紙飛行機！
（篠山(しのやま)）ん？
Welcome back, Director Nanbara.
（堀(ほり)）おかえりなさい 南原局長
How are things?
（南原）どう？
The two countries involved
are cooperating,
（堀）件(くだん)の２国が連携し
and the UN General Assembly
will denounce the situation.
国連総会にて
非難声明を発表すると
We are currently requesting support
from the U.S.
現在 米国に助勢を要請中です
DIRECTOR'S OFFICE
（南原）橘アイコを東京に移送する
I'm moving Aiko Tachibana to Tokyo.
And Professor Isazu, too, of course.
もちろん 伊佐津博士もね
What?
えっ？
今回は
確保できたからいいようなものの
We were fortunate that we got her back.
人工生体がらみの研究が
Artificial organism research
has long been the target
他国の諜報活動や
テロ組織の標的になっているのは
of both foreign intelligence
and terrorist groups.
由良俊英(ゆらとしひで)の論文が出る前から
明らかなことなのに…
We've known that since before
Toshihide Yura's essay.
（堀）
あっちは設備環境が
だんちですしね
They have far better
research facilities there.
Aiko Tachibana is not
the private property of Kiryu Research.
橘アイコは
桐生研の私有財産じゃないのよ
If only the government
had seen the importance
（堀）
国がセル･アセンブラの
産業重要性を
of building Cell Assemblers sooner,
もう少し 早く認めていれば
we would have the advantage, wouldn't we?
（堀）
主導権は
こちらにあったはずなんですよね
That's painful to hear.
耳が痛いわ
（堀）僭越(せんえつ)でした
My apologies.
We'll move Yuya Kanzaki
in Moriyama's vehicle.
（小佐波）
神崎雄哉は森山(もりやま)の車で移送する
Take the set routes
to headquarters.
それぞれ指定のルートで
対策本部へ
了解
Roger.
（アイコ）あの！
（小佐波）ん？
-Excuse me!
-Yes?
もう会えませんか？ あの人には
Will I be able to see him again?
He still needs to be dealt with properly.
彼には
相応の処遇が待っているから
うっ
あっ！
うわっ
What's going on?
何だ？
You stay here!
お前は残れ！
（部下）襲撃！
It's an attack!
Wait!
（楓(かえで)）待って！
-Thanks!
-Get to Haruka's car!
（雄哉）助かる！
（楓）遙香(はるか)の車に！
-Tachibana!
-Wait!
（雄哉）橘を！
（楓）ちょ…！
（部下）ぐわっ！
あっ！ 新手！
There's more!
（雄哉 荒い息）
An assault vehicle?
Are they government?
特務車両！ 政府か！
-What?
-Kanzaki!
（小佐波）なにっ！
（アイコ）神崎君！
Tachibana!
橘！
うわっ！
ああっ！
（アイコ）ねえ ホントなの？
Is it true?
本当に
お母さんと亮太(りょうた)は生きてるの？
Are Mom and Ryota really alive?
Those people said they were dead!
あの人たち
２人は死んだって言ってた！
What do you think?
君はどう思う？
I don't know. But I hope they're alive!
分からない…
でも 生きていてほしい！
I want to believe that they're alive!
生きてるって信じたい！
撤収！
Pull out!
Damn!
くそっ！
（伊佐津）
失態などという
レベルの問題じゃないぞ！
This isn't just any mistake!
I'll handle this.
手は打つわ
I'll do it right now.
ええ 直ちに
Shall we involve state police?
県警に捜索させますか？
できるわけないでしょう
You know we can't.
As everyone knows,
the Harinoki Tunnel in the east
（篠山）
周知のとおり
東側から爆心地へと至る針ノ木隧道(はりのきずいどう)
and the cable car tunnel
from Tateyama in the west
および 西側 立山(たてやま)方面からの
ケーブルトンネルは
have both been sealed off by the Matter.
いずれも
マターによって封鎖されている
Therefore, for this mission
よって 本作戦においては
we have no choice but to take a route
峡谷本線を遡上(そじょう)するルートを経(へ)て
that follows the valley rail line
to Primary Point.
プライマリー･ポイントへと
到達する以外に策はない
In particular,
after we pass the gate at K2,
特に
門番が立ちはだかるＫ２より奥
エリア３(スリー)以降は未知の区域だ
Area Three and beyond is uncharted.
No Diver has entered and returned alive.
踏み入って
生還したダイバーはおらず
Evidence has no data,
よって エビデンスどころか
and we don't know what kind
of Matter we'll run into.
遭遇するマターのカテゴリーすら
判明していない
過酷な任務になるだろうが…
This will be a rough mission.
We already know that! What else?
（楓）
そんなことは分かってんの！
で？
The mission commences
before dawn, at 4:30 a.m.
行動開始は
明朝 日の出前 ０４３０(マルヨンサンマル)
１時間前までに各自 準備完了を
Complete preparations one hour prior.
Shiraishi has transported
all your equipment here.
皆の装備は
白石(しらいし)がこちらに移しておいた
君たちになら 必ず成し遂げられる
I know you guys can pull this off.
健闘を期待する
I expect your best.
-Wilco!
（４人）ウィルコー！
あっ
（一樹(かずき)）自己紹介！
Hello, there.
I'm Kazuki Minase.
俺 水瀬(みなせ)一樹
あっ 橘… 橘アイコです
I'm Aiko Tachibana.
Nice to meet you, Tachibana.
よろしく 橘さん
The guy over there is my friend,
Yoshihiko Sagami.
んで あの人が俺のバディ
相模芳彦(さがみよしひこ)さん
Nice to meet you.
よろしく
（アイコ）あっ ども…
Hello.
自衛隊特戦出身の超スゴ腕
He's ex-special forces,
so he's super elite.
And that over there is Kaede Misawa.
それから あっちが三沢(みさわ)楓
She's a bitch.
（一樹）ヤなヤツ
（アイコ）あっ
痛(いて)っ！
I can hear you!
聞こえてるっつうの！
Kaede is just very frank.
（一樹）さー...
（遙香）楓は自分に素直なだけよ
I'm Haruka Seri. Nice to meet you.
芹(せり)遙香　よろしく
あっ よろしくお願いします
It's nice to meet you, too.
Tachibana.
（白石）橘さん
（２人）ん？
Come here.
ちょっといい？
あっ… はい
Yeah, sure.
These are the rations for the mission.
（白石）
これ 作戦で持ってくレーション
Rations?
（アイコ）レーション？
Portable meals.
（白石）携帯食料よ
Try it out to see if you can stomach it.
食べられるかどうか 試してみて
はい…
Okay.
あっ うん… おいしいです
It's really good.
（白石）そう よかった
Phew, that's good
It's the usual stuff, isn't it?
（楓）
どうせ いつものやつでしょ？
I swear I'll protect that girl.
俺 絶対 あの子を守りますから！
（楓）うまい
（相模）へいへい
俺のことも守ってくれよな
Yeah, yeah.
Make sure you protect me, too.
脳波を管理する… 装置？
A device that monitors my brain waves?
マインドスキャナという
It's a Mind Scanner.
A Mind Scanner?
（アイコ）マインド… スキャナ？
Yes. I want you to put this
on your forehead.
ああ
これを額に貼っておいてほしい
I have to get you to Primary Point
（雄哉）
君には脳も体も健康な状態で
プライマリー･ポイントまで
with your body and mind
in good, healthy condition.
たどりついてもらわないと
いけないから
（アイコ）ちょっ ちょっと待って
（雄哉）ん？
Hold on!
（アイコ）
冗談… じゃないんだよね？
This isn't a joke, right?
ホントにこれから…
We really are
going into the Area...
エリアの中に…
Yuya! There's trouble!
（黒瀬）雄哉！ ヤバいぞ！
（２人）あっ
（黒瀬）マターが！
It's the Matter!
MAJOR MATTER ACTIVITY
（アナウンサー）
繰り返し
お伝えします
I repeat,
the Chief Cabinet Secretary
just held an emergency press conference
内閣官房長官は
先ほど
マリグナント･マター
侵食域
announcing that major
Malignant Matter activity
通称 マリグナント
エリア内におきまして
has been observed
in the contaminated area,
マターによる
大活性活動が観測された
との緊急会見を
行いました
also known as the Malignant Area.
あっ
この大活性は２年前に起きました
バースト以来の規模となるもので
This is the most activity observed
since the Burst two years ago.
Beyond promptly summoning
all related government officials
政府は総理大臣官邸
危機管理センターに
to the Crisis Control Center
at the prime minister's home,
首相および各官僚を
至急 招集するとともに
緊急災害対策本部の設置を視野に
準備を進めており
the government is establishing
an emergency disaster control center,
and has stated the situation
エリア内外
および周辺域は
in and around the Area
is extremely precarious.
予断を許さない状況に
あるものと言えそうです
At the request of the local government,
なお 現在
自治体の要請に基づき
the Self-Defense Forces is preparing
for disaster relief efforts.
自衛隊部隊の災害派遣活動も
進められている模様ですが
However, since this could entail use
of military force against the Matter,
マターに対する牽制(けんせい)を目的とした
武力行使も想定されるため
政府は我が国 初となる
it is believed that the government
will enact the country's first ever
Civil Protection Order.
国民保護等派遣命令に
切り替えるものと思われており
In the wake of this,
これに伴い
fierce protests by opposing
civic organizations is expected.
反対する市民団体による
激しい抗議活動も予想…
くっ…！
Nearly all remaining security cameras
in the Area have gone down.
エリア内で生き残っていた
モニターカメラ
ほとんど いったそうです
Crisis Control is launching drones.
官邸地下がドローンを飛ばせと
They will be useless.
役になんて立たないわよ
僕もそう言ったんですが…
I told them the same thing.
おっ
Self-Defense Forces vehicles
are now driving past me.
（リポーター）
ええ〜 今 自衛隊の車両が
通過しております
マターに向けて
麻酔弾を発射するものと思われます
They're holding tranquilizer missiles
to be fired at the Matter.
This screws things up.
（黒瀬）まずいな
If security at the Gate is tightened,
ゲートのセキュリティが
強化されたら
even Divers could have trouble
getting into the Area.
ダイバーでもエリア内に
入れなくなるかもしれん
（ガッシャーン）
Shiraishi's checking on
any activity near the Gate now.
（篠山）
今 白石に
ゲート周辺の動きを確認させてる
Got it. I'll contact you
if anything happens.
分かった
また何かあれば 連絡する
The prime minister will back the
ruling party's Matter eradication faction.
（南原）与党内のマター殲滅(せんめつ)派が
首相と接触するのよ
これから ちょっと牽制(けんせい)
This will be a showdown.
（伊佐津）
何度も言うが
I'll say it again.
The grand result of our research
is Aiko Tachibana. Next to her,
我々の研究の集大成である
橘アイコに比べれば
the prototypes and samples
left inside the Area are mere trash.
エリアに残っている
プロトやサンプルなど
がらくた同然だ
When you say "our",
don't you mean just your allies?
（南原）
その我々というのは
あなたの身内だけでしょ？
（伊佐津）君は分かっていない
You don't understand.
Project ACO isn't just yours.
（南原）
プロジェクトＡＣＯ(エーシーオー)は
あなた１人のものじゃないの
It's AICO.
（伊佐津）ＡＩＣＯ(エーアイシーオー)だ
Artificial and Intelligent
Cellular Organism.
Cellular Organism
由良が橘アイコによって
You'd better not forget that
Yura fundamentally transformed
this project due to Aiko Tachibana.
このプロジェクトを
本質的に変化させたことを
忘れてもらっては困る
Naho,
I'm visiting relatives for a while.
あっ！
んん…
-Aiko!
-Sister!
（アイコの母）アイコ！
（亮太）お姉ちゃん
Can you see us, Aiko?
分かる？ アイコ
What is this? Where am I?
（アイコ）
何これ… どこ？
It's Dr. Isazu. Is this the hospital?
伊佐津先生… 病院？
Oh, right. I was in an accident.
そっか… 私 事故に…
Evacuate immediately!
（スタッフＡ）緊急退避します
（スタッフＢ）うわ〜！
（アイコ）
いや！ 逃げなくちゃ！
I have to escape!
-Okay, you're all set.
-Take off!
（研究員１）よし 大丈夫だ
（研究員２）離陸させろ
What? I got away, didn't I?
（アイコ）
あれ？ 私 逃げたんじゃ…
What's this?
（アイコ）
何…？
Who is that?
誰？
A girl? No, it's Ryota!
女の子？ 違う 亮太だ！
His hair is so long.
髪 伸びてる…
Mom!
お母さん！
はっ！
Was I asleep?
私… 寝てた？
You were.
ああ
I had a dream. Mom and Ryota were in it.
夢 見てた
お母さんと亮太がいた
It was like they really were alive.
ホントに生きてるみたいだった
What you saw is reality.
その光景は現実だ
What?
えっ？
You actually saw that yourself.
君は実際に その目で見たんだよ
How can you know that?
（アイコ）
なんで そんなことが分かるの？
Right now,
you possess the ability to see that.
君には今 それを見る力が
備わってるんだ
-What?
-Remember what I told you?
（アイコ）えっ？
（雄哉）言ったろ
君は今 人間じゃない
You're not a human right now.
あっ…
I can believe you, right?
信じていいんだよね？
I can believe your story
爆心地に行けば
that if I go to Ground Zero,
I can save Mom and Ryota, right?
お母さんと亮太が
救えるかもしれないっていう―
あなたの話…
私 行く！
生き残ってくれた家族を救いに！
I'm going! My family is still alive
and I'm going to save them!
Let's reconfirm.
（黒瀬）
再度 確認する
遮断堰(しゃだんぜき)を越えたら
Once past the Gate,
maintain radio silence
until reaching the first camp in K1.
最初のキャンプ予定地である
Ｋ１まで 連絡は取り合えない
以降 キャンプ予定地にも
After that, with all the equipment
ダイバーや かつての
マター対策庁の特務編成部隊が
stored at the camps by Divers
and CAAC Special Forces,
残していった物資が
備蓄されているが
the absolute longest
the whole mission can take is...
すべてを使っても
全工程の猶予は…
10日だな
Ten days.
１週間で
One week.
（３人）あっ？
Stick exactly to the plan.
厳守でお願いします
She's losing consciousness?
（黒瀬）意識が薄れてる？
Is it the other Aiko Tachibana?
What's the cause?
もう１人の橘アイコのか？
原因は？
I can't say.
（雄哉）
何とも…
とにかく 意識が消える前に
たどりつかないと
But we must arrive
before she loses consciousness completely.
You're right.
I'll bolster our backup plans.
（黒瀬）
そうだな
バックアップ態勢を強化する
Thanks.
（雄哉）お願いします
Hey! Wait!
（アイコ）
ああっ ちょ… ちょっと！
Come back!
ちょっと待って！
I said wait!
待ってったら！
（アイコ）わっ！
I told you I would put it on for you.
だから
着せてあげるって言ったのに
Thank you.
すみません
慌てずに 少しずつ慣らして
Don't rush it.
Let it grow on you.
Okay.
はい
This isn't simply an undergarment.
It's your partner.
（白石）
これは単なる下着じゃなくて
あなたのパートナー
It links with your muscles
to help you lift heavy objects,
筋肉に連動して
重い物を持つのをアシストしたり
and protect you from physical shock.
衝撃から守ってくれたりするの
エリア内は危険だから
It's dangerous in the Area,
専用のスーツを
身に着ける必要があるの
so we have to wear specialized suits.
ひとまず Ｋ１で
専用の移動車を手に入れるまでは
For now, until we get
the specialized vehicles in K1,
ダイバーと同じスーツ 着てね
you'll wear the same suit as the Divers.
There! Your Live Suit is good to go.
はい！
インナーライブスーツの出来上がり
あー
（白石）
それと… ニュートリションボトル
And here's your nutriobags.
Artificial organisms are living beings,
so they need to eat and excrete.
人工生体は生き物だからね
食事と排泄も大事
Let's get these hooked up.
ボトルをつなげて…
（雄哉）
ダイバーたちには
Let's not tell
the Divers about the link
between you and your duplicate.
君の体と複製体との関係は
伏せておいてほしい
Really?
（アイコ）えっ？
Your body is a composite
of real and artificial parts,
（雄哉）
生身と人工生体との
合成体である君の体は
so you excrete bioactive substances
that attract the Matter.
マターを引き寄せる
生理活性物質を発生させる
That is, the Matter is drawn to you.
いわば 君はマターの好物だ
What? No way!
えっ！ ちょっ そんな…
Don't worry.
心配ない
I have a drug that will
suppress that bioactivity.
だから それを抑えるための薬を
投与しておきたい
あっ！
それ 病院で打っていたのと…
Is that what
they gave me at the hospital?
同じものだ 安心してくれ
It's the same. Relax, it's safe.
I don't want to worry the Divers.
ダイバーの皆の不安を
煽(あお)りたくないんだ
Okay.
分かった
（カチャッ）
But that means Dr. Isazu knew
でも じゃあ
伊佐津先生は全部知ってたのね
about my body this whole time.
私の体のこと…
He is a doctor, after all.
医者だからな
Tachibana.
（白石）橘さん
Yes?
ああっ はい
I'm going to plug the connector
into your Live Suit.
じゃあ コネクタを
ライブスーツに接続するわね
Okay.
はい
It measures your vitals and syncs to you.
あなたのバイタルを読み込んで
同期するから
It'll feel weird.
ちょっと くるわよ
（アイコ）うわっ…
気持ち悪い！
That so creepy!
（楓）
そうそう
初めて着たとき そうだった
I know! It was the same
the first time I wore one.
You'll get used to it.
（白石）すぐに慣れるわ
Let's get through the Gate
before it's sealed off.
（篠山）
封鎖される前にゲートをくぐるぞ
We can't guarantee your safety in there.
（係員）
この状況です
責任は負えませんよ
If I expected you to,
I would never be able to do this job.
（篠山）
そんなもの 期待してたら
やってられんよ
この仕事は
The tranquilizer missiles
have taken effect,
（役員）
現在は自衛隊の麻酔弾が効いており
and the situation is quieting down,
事態は沈静化していますが
いつまた活性化するか
全く読めません
but we have no idea
when it will become active again.
（事務員）
東京から指示 くだりました！
We have received orders from Tokyo!
Orders as of 4:42 a.m.
Seal off Aimoto Dam!
（係員）
４時42分 発令
愛本(あいもと)遮断堰 封鎖！
（サイレン）
Are you kidding?
We just let some guys through.
（係員）
何だよ さっき１つ通したぞ
By order of the government,
（アナウンス）
こちらは 国土交通省です
we will now be sealing off the dam.
まもなく 通過門が封鎖されます
All Divers within the Area
must immediately evacuate.
エリア内に滞在している
ダイバーの皆さんは
すみやかに退去してください
I repeat...
繰り返します…
She's inside the Area?
エリア内だと？
Apparently, yes.
どうやら…
（伊佐津）くっ！
All right, let's get moving.
（相模）
んじゃ ぼちぼち行きますか
〜
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey